export default Dpe6 = [

    {
        question: "1. Which of the following spectrum is look like a fingerprints ?",
        options: ["All",
            "Visible spectrum",
            "Line spectrum",
            "Band spectrum"],
        correct_option: "Line spectrum"
    },
    {
        question: "3. Give an example for continuous spectrum",
        options: ["None",
            "Colour of sky",
            "Rainbow",
            "Tube light"],
        correct_option: "Rainbow"
    },
    {
        question: "4. -l to +l including '0' falls under the",
        options: ["Spin quantum number",
            "Angular momentum quantum number",
            "Principle quantum number",
            "Magnetic quantum number"],
        correct_option: "Principle quantum number"
    },
    {
        question: "5. Which of the following is true according to quantum mechanical model of an atom ?",
        options: ["All are correct",
            "Simultaneously the position and velocity of an electron cannot be measured accuraetly",
            "Electrons are present in a particular region around the nucleus",
            "it was proposed by Erwin Schrodinger"],
        correct_option: "All are correct"
    },
    {
        question: "6. How many number of orbitals are there in the sub - shell of a magnetic quantum number if l = 3 ?",
        options: ["3",
            "7",
            "1",
            "5"],
        correct_option: "7"
    },
    {
        question: "7. What is meant by Aufbau ?",
        options: ["Fall down",
            "Building up",
            "Creation",
            "ANone"],
        correct_option: "Building up"
    },
    {
        question: "8. Spin quantum number shows",
        options: ["Spin of an electron about its own axis",
            "All",
            "Size of atom",
            "Energy of atom"],
        correct_option: "Spin of an electron about its own axis"
    },
    {
        question: "9. Who introduced magnetic quantum number ?",
        options: ["Lande",
            "Sommerfeld",
            "Bohr",
            "Goudsmit"],
        correct_option: "Lande"
    },

    {
        question: "11. Bohr's atomic model explains spectrum of",
        options: ["He+",
            "H",
            "Li+2",
            "All"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },
    {
        question: "12. Which principle states that two electrons of the same atom can't have all same quantum numbers ?",
        options: ["Flemming's left hand rule",
            "Hund's rule",
            "Pauli's exclusion principle",
            "Aufbau principle"],
        correct_option: "Pauli's exclusion principle"
    },
    {
        question: "13. Which element has duplet configuration ?",
        options: ["H",
            "B",
            "C",
            "He"],
        correct_option: "He"
    },
    {
        question: "14. Value of  'n' is",
        options: ["2 to m",
            "All",
            "1 to n",
            "0 to n-1"],
        correct_option: "1 to n"
    },
    {
        question: "15. The quantum number which explains about size and energy of orbit or shell is",
        options: ["ml",
            "ms",
            "n",
            "l"],
        correct_option: "n"
    },
    {
        question: "16. The n + l value of 3d orbital is",
        options: ["3",
            "5",
            "4",
            "6"],
        correct_option: "5"
    },
    {
        question: "17. Orbitals having same energy are called",
        options: ["Degenerate orbitals",
            "Hybrid orbitals",
            "Atomic orbitals",
            "Pure orbitals"],
        correct_option: "Degenerate orbitals"
    },
    {
        question: "18. The number of electrons in p - sub shell",
        options: ["11",
            "10",
            "14",
            "6"],
        correct_option: "6"
    },
    {
        question: "19. f-orbitals are present in",
        options: ["N- shells",
            "L- shells",
            "K- shells",
            "M- shells"],
        correct_option: "N- shells"
    },
    {
        question: "20. The subshells present in L- shell are",
        options: ["s , p and d",
            "s, p, d and f",
            "s and d",
            "s and p"],
        correct_option: "s and p"
    },
    {
        question: "21. Shape of p - orbital is",
        options: ["No shape",
            "Spherical",
            "Double dumbell",
            "Dumbell"],
        correct_option: "Dumbell"
    },
    {
        question: "22. The quantum number give shape nof orbital",
        options: ["ms",
            "l",
            "ml",
            "n"],
        correct_option: "l"
    },
    {
        question: "23. 1s22s22p1 is the electronic configuration of",
        options: ["Boron",
            "Nitrogen",
            "Carbon",
            "Beryllium"],
        correct_option: "Boron"
    },

]